You are being watched.
你被監視著
The government has a secret system--
政府有一套秘密設備…
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
一台每時每刻監視你的機器
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror,
我設計這個機器偵測恐怖行動
but it sees everything...
但它卻看到了一切
Violent crimes involving ordinary people.
普通人捲入的暴力犯罪
The government considers these people irrelevant.
政府認為這些人無關緊要
We don't.
我們不敢茍同
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
為逃避官方追捕，我們秘密行動
You will never find us.
你不可能找到我們
But victim or perpetrator,
但無論是受害者還是罪犯
if your number's up, we'll find you.
一旦你的號碼出現，我們就會找到你
疑犯追踪
第三季        第十八集
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：飞翔的鸡 HelloAgnes lydia萌 LordVader
校对：lydia萌      字幕支持：饭离烨
字幕特效：飞翔的鸡
異常檢測
地點：伊拉克摩蘇爾
事件分析…
事件分析
地點：摩蘇爾大壩
水力發電機丟失 6台
Bear!
大熊！
No, no, no, no.
不，不，不
He found the treats.
他找到獎勵零食了
Come on. Go!
行了，別這樣！
He's a military working dog, Finch.
他是只軍犬，芬奇
Search and rescue,
搜索和營救
trained to track people, uncover explosives.
受訓跟蹤敵人，查找爆炸物
I suppose Moliere is no challenge at all.
莫裏哀完全不堪一擊
Maybe I should have Bear track down Ms. Shaw.
也許我該讓大熊跟蹤肖女士
I thought you put her on the new number.
我以為你給她新號碼了
I did, but communication is not her strong suit.
我是給了，不過她不喜歡聯絡
Tally-ho, Finch.
出現了，芬奇
Our engineer's in sight.
我們的工程師出現了
These turbine blades are missing a customs clearance.
這些渦輪葉片還沒報關
As soon as they get to Kenya,
一運到肯尼亞
the locals will demand a bribe to clear them.
當地海關要索賄才會同意入關
But, since we're out of time,
不過現在我們時間不夠
call Benny at the Mombasa customs house.
打給蒙巴薩海關的本尼
<i>Tell him there's a bottle of Kentucky bourbon</i>
<i>跟他說這裏有一瓶</i>
<i>with his name on it.</i>
<i>印著他名字的波旁酒</i>
瑪利亞·馬丁內斯
已連接
Our girl's got more foreign contacts than Reese and I combined.
這妹子的外國聯繫人比我和裏斯加起來還多
<i>Indeed. Maria Martinez is quite the world traveler.</i>
<i>那當然，瑪麗亞·馬丁內斯蹤跡遍及全球</i>
Masters in engineering from Stanford.
斯坦福大學的工程學碩士
She works for Hydral Corp, a private energy company.
她在水力公司工作，一家私營能源企業
She's currently working on reconstruction projects
她當前正在第三世界國家
in third-world countries.
開展改建工程
She digs wells?
挖井？
Builds multimillion-dollar generators is more like it.
建造數百萬美元級別的發電機
Her last project was replacing the generators
她上一項工程是替換伊拉克
指尖上的能源
Hydral 公司
inside a hydroelectric dam in Iraq.
一座水電大壩的發電機
Maria!
瑪麗亞！
Great work here, adding the GPS trackers.
幹得漂亮，加上了GPS追蹤器
Considering everything we went through
我們費盡千辛萬苦
to get those generators into the country and assemble them.
才把發電機送入境再組裝
Can't afford to lose anything, like we did in Iraq.
絕對不能像伊拉克那樣再丟了
We have to make sure our supply chain and sources are beyond reproach.
必須確保供應鏈和來源絕對安全
<i>That's Ken Davis, Maria's boss.</i>
<i>這是肯·戴維斯，瑪麗亞的老闆</i>
<i>He runs Hydral Corp.</i>
</i>水力公司是他開的</i>
Excuse me, I have to take this.
抱歉，我得接個電話
<i>Hello?</i>
<i>喂？</i>
<i>Hello.</i>
<i>你好</i>
Hello.
你好
<i>The package is ready.</i>
<i>包裹準備就緒</i>
But we can't talk on the phone.
但我們不能在電話裏談
Meet at the usual place <i>in an hour.</i>
一小時後老地方見
Yeah.
好
Didn't see that comin'.
真是出人意料
Maria just took a five-finger discount on a GPS tracker.
瑪麗亞順手牽走了一個GPS追蹤器
I'm sorry, I have to go.
抱歉，我得走了
Everything all right?
你沒事吧？
Just a meeting with a supplier I forgot about.
忘了會見一個供應商
- Mm, okay. - Thank you.
- 好吧
- 謝謝
And she lied to her boss.
她對老闆說了謊
Plus this delivery of a mysterious package?
外加那個待交付的神秘包裹？
Sounds like pre-operational tactics.
像是一次預演戰術
Tactics? Of what?
戰術？什麼戰術？
A terrorist cell.
恐怖小組的
If Maria were a relevant number,
如果瑪麗亞是相關號碼
she would fall under the government's purview.
她會進入政府的管轄範圍
Maybe the machine got its wires crossed.
也許機器電線搭錯了
Ever since it's had that cochlear cuckoo on speed dial--
才會把那只壞耳蝸的布谷鳥列入聯繫人
I fail to see how its relationship with Ms. Groves
我沒看出葛洛弗小姐
has anything to do with this.
與機器的關係對此有何影響
Do you really think that our number could be a terrorist?
你真認為這個號碼會是恐怖分子？
I believe Shaw's gonna need our backup.
我認為肖需要我們支援
<i>Hello, Harold.</i>
<i>你好，哈羅德</i>
You wanted to talk to me? Or her?
你想跟我談？還是跟她？
How did you-- Never mind.
你怎麼…算了
<i>I was curious--</i>
<i>我很好奇…</i>
I don't know anything about your little number, Harold.
我對你那小號碼一無所知，哈羅德
<i>I'm pursing</i> <i>a much larger objective.</i>
<i>我關心的是一個大得多的目標</i>
The chip that Decima stole.
德西瑪公司偷走的芯片
Has the machine directed you to--
機器指示你去…
That chip has already been back-engineered
那個芯片已經被破解
and thousands of copies are being generated
我們說話這會
as we speak.
已經復製出成千上萬個了
Enough to run Samaritan <i>at full power.</i>
</i>足夠讓撒瑪利亞全負荷運轉</i>
The machine has alerted me
機器已經警告我
that our elusive adversary is back in town.
我們神出鬼沒的對手回來了
Eliminating him might be our last chance
除掉他可能是
at stopping Samaritan.
終止撒瑪利亞的最後機會
I'll be in touch the next time my ear starts burning.
等我下次耳朵癢了再聯繫
Do you have my position?
你知道我的位置嗎？
Good.
很好
I've made a new friend,
我交了個新朋友
but I'm not feeling particularly sociable.
但我現在不是很想寒暄
Have our asset at Parkhurst Security go blind.
把我們在帕克赫斯特安保的設備關掉
信號丟失
追蹤對像
化名：約翰·格裏爾
安保鏡頭離線
正在轉為音頻模式
追蹤對像
化名：約翰·格裏爾
安保鏡頭離線
正在轉為音頻模式
體重：
間隔：
距離：
音頻分析中
84,024千克
1.023秒
0.976米
目標出現
Direction?
方向？
Got it.
收到
A little volume, please.
來點聲音
追蹤對像
化名：約翰·格裏爾
體重：84,024千克
間隔：1.023秒
距離：0.976米
音頻輸入飽和
目標丟失
正在轉為GPS搜尋
目標出現
There you are.
找到你了
Going dark.
隱蔽
Rendezvous in two minutes.
兩分鐘後見
What the hell, lady?
你幹什麼，女士？
Sorry.
抱歉
Thought you were my uncle.
還以為你是我叔叔
Beirut.
貝魯特
- Baghdad. - Baghdad for masguf.
- 巴格達
- 巴格達烤魚
Saddam knew his fish.
薩達姆很懂魚
I'll give you that.
說的不錯
But shawarma?
不過切片烤肉
Beirut, hands down.
貝魯特多得是
He can't go back.
他回不來了
I'm doing everything I can.
我能做的都做了
They won't release him.
他們不放他走
We must do something now.
我們得做點什麼了
I traced Maria's earlier phone call.
我監聽了瑪麗亞之前的電話
Jamal Risha is an Iraqi who immigrated to the US
賈馬爾·瑞捨是伊拉克人
two years ago.
兩年前移民到美國
This man, he won't see me.
這個人，他不見我
He won't even talk to me.
他甚至不跟我說話
He's the only thing blocking Omar.
就是他困住了奧馬爾
We can't just leave my brother behind.
不能丟下我兄弟不管
Finch, you hear that?
芬奇，聽到了嗎？
According to the Immigration and Customs Enforcement database,
根據移民局和海關數據庫
Omar Risha was detained by the Department Of Homeland Security
奧馬爾·瑞捨一周前到達肯尼迪國際機場後
扣留--特殊行政管制
after landing at JFK a week ago.
被國土安全局扣留了
Where are they holding him now?
現在他們把他關在哪？
A high-security detention center in Manhattan
曼哈頓的一個高度安全拘留中心
under special administrative measures.
實行特殊行政管制
Those are reserved for terrorism suspects.
這是關押恐怖活動嫌疑人的
We have a small window of opportunity to make an impact.
我們能起作用的希望很小
This should open their eyes.
這個能讓他們開開眼界
Big bombs keep coming in little packages.
小包裹裏都是大炸彈
Like the shoe bomber.
就像扔鞋彈的
Good luck.
好運
Thank you, Jamal.
謝謝，賈馬爾
I'll keep eyes on Jamal.
我盯著賈馬爾
See if he has any other contacts.
看看他還跟誰聯繫
I'll stick close to our friend Maria.
我繼續盯緊我們的瑪麗亞
Figure out what the hell she's gotten herself into.
看看她到底趟了什麼渾水
Thanks for the sandwich.
謝謝你的三明治
But why do you gotta drag me all the way up here,
但是你幹嘛費老大勁把我拽來
just to watch your girl snap a few memories?
就為了看姑娘拍留念照呢？
When's the last time you saw a New Yorker from The Village
你什麼時候見過紐約市民
take tourist photos at the UN?
來聯合國拍留念照？
That's a good point.
說得好啊
If you're so smart, what do you need me for?
你這麼聰明，拉我過來幹嘛？
You can't park here!
這裏不准停車！
Security precaution.
安全防範
Yeah, I got one of those.
嗯，我知道
Way to make yourself useful, Lionel.
發揮你用處的時候到了，萊諾
You know, I don't understand all the hoopla with the UN anyway.
我不理解聯合國干的那些破事
<i>Bunch of silver-spoon</i> <i>bureaucrats, if you ask me.</i>
<i>一群出身貴族的官僚</i>
And don't even get me started
更別提那個
with the extraterritorial privileges either.
什麼治外法權了
Oh, I should've just stolen a badge.
我真該偷個警徽過來的
How many countries you think there are in the UN?
你覺得聯合國裏有多少國家？
- Like 50-something? - 193.
- 大概50個？
- 193個
You know, you really should get out more.
你真該多出去走走
Learn something about other cultures.
多學學其他文化
What are you talking about?
這算什麼話？
I just ate a falafel.
我剛吃了個中東三明治
Yeah, and you got some on your tie.
是啊，還有些留在領帶上了
That's the second tie this week.
這周的第二條領帶了
Maria's taking photos of the interior of the UN compound.
瑪麗亞給聯合國廣場內部拍了照
Surveillance is the last planning stage before an attack.
監視是進攻前最後的步驟
Wait.
等等
She's not shooting the compound.
她不是在拍聯合國廣場
She's taking pictures of this <i>guy.</i>
她在拍這個人
Photo's on its way, Finch.
照片傳過去了，芬奇
I don't know who the suit is.
我不認識這個人
The man in the photo is Rene Lapointe,
照片裏的人叫雷內·拉普安特
a French diplomat and current United Nations High Commissioner for refugees.
法國外交官，也是聯合國難民署高級專員
He's responsible for approving the asylum request
他負責批准賈馬爾兄弟奧馬爾的
of Jamal's brother Omar.
政治避難請求
He just triggered our Jihad Jane to go live.
他剛剛激活了我們的聖戰分子
<i>Maria just stopped his car.</i>
<i>瑪麗亞截住了他的車</i>
She's putting something--
她放了什麼東西上去
<i>Miss Shaw, what is it?</i>
<i>肖女士，什麼東西？</i>
<i>Oh, that was smooth.</i>
<i>動作真是流暢啊</i>
<i>I couldn't have done</i> <i>that better myself.</i>
<i>我也不過如此</i>
She just placed the GPS tracker onto Lapointe's limo.
她剛在拉普安特豪車上放了GPS追蹤器
<i>She's tracking him.</i>
<i>她在跟蹤他</i>
Taxi!
出租車！
<i>And, more importantly...</i>
<i>更重要的是…</i>
I think we just identified her target.
我想我們已經找到她的目標了
All these fat-cat diplomats travel all over the world,
這些有權有勢的外交官拿著別人的錢
eatin' on someone else's dime
周遊世界
while they talk about feeding the poor.
還滿嘴說著要救濟窮人
Maybe you ought to consider applying for a passport.
也許你可以考慮辦個護照
I have a passport.
我有護照
My ex and I went to Saint Thomas for our honeymoon.
我前妻和我去聖托馬斯島度的蜜月
You mean the US Virgin Islands?
你是說美國的維爾京群島？
Okay, there's our girl.
我們的姑娘來了
<i>Your engineer pulls one hell of a changing act.</i>
<i>你的工程師換衣服可真快</i>
<i>Yeah, dressed to kill.</i>
<i>嗯，光鮮亮麗去殺人</i>
She's still got that package in her shoulder bag.
那個包裹還在她包裏
Go ahead, I'll watch the front.
去吧，我守著前門
We might have a problem, Finch.
可能有麻煩了，芬奇
<i>Maria's closing in on her target.</i>
<i>瑪麗亞正在接近她的目標</i>
You want proof? There's proof.
你想要證據？這就是證據
Is everything all right, Ms. Shaw?
一切還好嗎，肖女士？
False alarm.
虛驚一場
Unless we're worried about paper cuts.
大不了就是被紙割傷
Sorry, do I know you?
抱歉，我們認識嗎？
Omar Risha is not a terrorist.
奧馬爾·瑞捨不是恐怖分子
He worked for US forces in Iraq
他為駐伊美軍工作
and for my company as a translator.
也是我們公司的翻譯
There's a recommendation in here from my boss Ken Davis.
這是我老闆肯·戴維斯的推薦信
What more proof do you want?
你還想要什麼證據？
Let me guess.
我猜
- You must be Maria? - In person.
- 你一定是瑪麗亞？
- 正是
Maria, the US Department Of Homeland Security
瑪麗亞，美國國土安全局
has asked me to weigh all the evidence
要求我在給避難者分級前
before classifying refugees.
慎重權衡所有證據
What evidence do you have to the contrary?
你有什麼反面證據？
That is confidential.
這是機密
But, let me assure you,
但是，我保證
Omar Risha will have a fair hearing.
奧馬爾·瑞捨會得到公平審訊
Now if you'll excuse me.
抱歉失陪了
Look, I get it.
我懂了
Just tell me...
直接告訴我…
what's the going rate?
需要多少錢吧
Are you insane?
你瘋了嗎？
I am not leaving until I get an answer.
你不回答我就不走
- Security! - Excuse me, ma'am.
- 保安！
- 抱歉，女士
Please come with us.
請跟我們來
Sorry, gentlemen.
抱歉，先生們
She's with me.
她跟我一起的
It's okay, I know her.
沒關係，我認識她
Allow me to take care of this.
請讓我來處理
Finch?
芬奇？
Maria was about to get tossed out
瑪麗亞剛要被趕出去的時候
when this guy stepped in.
這個人插手了
新消息
收信人：未知
發信人：未知
You work with Ken Davis.
你跟肯·戴維斯共事
He's a friend.
他是我朋友
I'm sorry about all this.
我很抱歉
I don't wanna burden you with my problems.
我不想讓你負擔我的麻煩
What's this all about?
究竟是怎麼回事？
My former interpreter from Iraq
我的前任翻譯是伊拉克人
is being held on suspicion of terrorism
現在被懷疑是恐怖分子
and might be deported.
可能會被驅逐出境
I know it's a false allegation.
我知道這項指控不成立
But that jerk won't believe me.
但那個混蛋不信我
Monsieur Lapointe may be lazy, even corrupt,
拉普安特先生可能懶散，甚至貪污
but you don't get all that power
但他那些權力
by being a nice guy.
也不是好人能得到的
There are ways around men like him.
對他這種人可以採取其他辦法
I don't know what else to do.
我不知道還能做什麼了
Perhaps I can help.
也許我能幫你
<i>Without companies</i> <i>like Hydral Corp</i>
<i>少了水力公司這種</i>
that build infrastructure,
建造公共設施的企業
the United Nations would never accomplish anything.
聯合國就無法有任何作為
Unfortunately, some of the old guard prefer
不幸的是，一些保守派
<i>to bite the hand that feeds.</i>
<i>反而恩將仇報</i>
Let me make a few calls.
我要打幾個電話
If you need anything else...
如果你有任何需要的話…
Thank you.
謝謝你
Looks like Maria just found herself a white knight.
看來瑪麗亞找到救星了
Christos Sevon.
克裏斯托·斯萬
A career diplomat from Greece currently serving
是希臘的職業外交官
on the UN Sustainable Energy program.
目前為聯合國可持續能源計劃效力
He raises funds to support reconstruction projects
他為改建工程籌集基金
like the one Maria worked on in Iraq.
就像瑪麗亞在伊拉克做的那種工程
Well, he's offered to help get Omar into the country.
他主動幫助奧馬爾入境
Let's hope that he doesn't live to regret that decision.
但願他不會後悔做這個決定
We need to get a look at that evidence against Omar.
我們得看到不利於奧馬爾的證據
Sounds like Omar could use a good lawyer.
奧馬爾貌似需要一名好律師
Perhaps it's time Mr. Reese and I
也許我和裏斯先生
did a little pro bono work.
也該做些公益工作了
How can I help you and your associates,
有什麼可以幫助您和合夥人？
Mr. Kingfisher?
金費捨先生？
My firm represents several refugees
我的公司代表若干在伊拉克
who worked for the US government in Iraq
為美國政府工作
now seeking asylum.
現在尋求庇護的避難者
There are concerns about refugees from Iraq
我們對伊拉克難民申請移民美國
immigrating to the US.
有一些顧慮
Yes, we're-- we're aware.
是的，我們…我們知道
One of our clients-- Omar Risha--
我的一個客戶，奧馬爾·瑞捨
is being detained for alleged links to terrorism.
由於所謂的「與恐怖主義有聯繫」正被拘留
I know Monsieur Risha's case well.
我很瞭解瑞捨先生的案子
In fact, I have to make a final decision on it this week.
其實，我們在這周內就要對此案做最終決定了
May I?
我可以看嗎？
If I'm to prepare a legal defense,
如果要準備辯護
I require all of the facts.
我需要瞭解所有事實
You may review it, but here.
你可以看，但只能在這
Thank you.
謝謝您
I received that letter from the Iraqi government last week.
我上周從伊拉克政府收到此信
The Ministry of the Interior say they have proof
內政部聲稱他們有證據
that Omar is involved in terrorist activity.
證明奧馬爾參與了恐怖主義活動
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Um, the Ministry of the Interior is hardly reliable.
內政部不是很可靠吧
It's full of former Shia militia members.
很多成員都是前什葉派民兵
They view Iraqis that helped American forces
他們認為幫助美軍的伊拉克人
as traitors.
是叛徒
Three years ago, two terrorists
三年前，兩個曾在伊拉克
who killed US soldiers in Iraq
殺害美軍士兵的恐怖分子
were discovered living in Bowling Green, Kentucky.
被發現居住在肯塔基州鮑林格林市
They fooled Immigration officials
他們假扮翻譯
by posing as former interpreters.
騙過了移民局官員
Yes, but, surely, such an isolated case
是的，但是這種單個案例
should not affect the plight of thousands.
也不該影響數千人的處境
I can't afford to put my signature
我承擔不起在一個潛在恐怖分子的
on an application of a potential terrorist,
申請表上簽字的後果
however small the probability.
不管其可能性有多小
If one more terrorist slips through,
再漏過一個恐怖分子
it will jeopardize all the other refugees seeking asylum.
就會危害其他所有尋求庇護的避難者
You understand.
你要理解
<i>Understood.</i>
<i>我理解</i>
- Thank you for your time. - Thank you.
- 感謝您的寶貴時間
- 謝謝
Well, it's difficult to determine the authenticity of the letter.
很難確定這封信的真實性
伊拉克共和國
內政部  秘書長
<i>Any new developments</i> <i>on your end, Ms. Shaw?</i>
<i>你那邊有新進展嗎，肖女士？</i>
She takes the 7 train to get home.
她坐7點的車回了家
Does that help?
這有用嗎？
Jamal, good news.
賈馬爾，好消息
I found someone in a position we can leverage.
我發現一個對我們有用的人
Call me back, and I'll explain.
回電話，我再給你解釋
Thank you.
謝謝你
You're welcome.
不客氣
- How many extra mags you got? - Extra mags? You serious?
- 你有多少額外彈夾？
- 額外彈夾？你沒搞錯？
Finch, we're gonna need some backup.
芬奇，我們需要支援
Mind?
不好意思
Personally, I prefer potassium chloride to chloroform.
我個人認為氯化鉀比氯仿更好
Acts quicker and no trace in postmortem toxicology.
見效更快，屍體不留痕跡
And the other thing about chloroform, it stinks.
而且氯仿還有個缺點，就是很臭
Who the hell was that?
這人到底是誰？
French Algerian.
法裔阿爾及利亞人
With a Maserin bolt knife.
帶著一把馬賽裏彈簧刀
I'd say French Foreign Legion.
肯定是法國外籍兵團的
You've made friends all over the world, Maria.
你的朋友真是遍佈全球，瑪麗亞
Foreign Legion?
外籍兵團？
Why would they wanna kill me?
他們為什麼要殺我？
I don't know. I don't speak French.
我不知道，我又不懂法語
Finch, what's our ETA on Captain America?
芬奇，我們的美國隊長什麼時候能到？
<i>Mr. Reese should be with you directly.</i>
<i>裏斯先生會直接去你那</i>
Stay close to the wall.
緊貼牆邊
I'm guessing this guy might have some friends.
我猜這人可能還有幾個同夥
Guess that falafel didn't slow you down.
看來三明治沒讓你身手變慢
Is that it? Any more?
就這些？還有嗎？
Maria, get down!
瑪麗亞，趴下！
<i>Your boy there's got issues.</i>
<i>你哥們有問題吧</i>
Hope that guy has health insurance.
但願那人有醫保
What's up with the Evel Knievel stunt?
那招特技表演哪兒學的？
They didn't teach you that in Marine jump school?
你在海軍跳傘學校沒學嗎？
Only if a 5-cent piece of lead won't get you out the door.
只是小線索就不勞你出門了
- But thanks for coming. - You're welcome.
- 多謝前來
- 不客氣
I'm sorry to interrupt, but who the hell are you guys?
抱歉打斷下，你們又是什麼人？
We're a lot like you, Ms. Martinez.
我們跟你很像，馬丁內斯女士
We help people in less fortunate circumstances.
我們幫助不走運的人
<i>We only require one thing</i> <i>in return for our services.</i>
<i>我們只求一個回報</i>
What's that?
什麼？
The truth.
實話
Why are you trying to get Omar Risha into the US?
你為什麼要幫奧馬爾·瑞捨來美國？
Omar was my interpreter on my last project.
奧馬爾是我做上個項目的翻譯
We were in a convoy transporting six generators
我們護送轉移六台發電機
from Kuwait to Iraq when we were ambushed.
從科威特轉到伊拉克時被伏擊了
I jumped into a ditch, about to be overrun,
我跳進壕溝裏，就要被擊敗的時候
when Omar jumped in next to me
奧馬爾跳到我旁邊
and shot two of the terrorists.
開槍打了兩個恐怖分子
The rest fled.
其餘的逃走了
He saved my life.
他救了我
Sounds like he deserves a medal.
應該獎勵塊金牌啊
After I left Iraq,
我離開伊拉克後
Omar started receiving death threats.
奧馬爾開始收到死亡恐嚇
If he's sent back, he'll be killed.
如果他被送回去，他會被殺的
What do French legionnaires have to do with this?
法國外籍兵團跟這事有什麼關係？
I don't know.
我不知道
The day before Omar left, he wanted to talk to me
奧馬爾離開前一天，他想找我談談
about some generators that went missing in Iraq.
關於在伊拉克丟的幾台發電機
He didn't wanna talk about it on the phone.
他不想在電話裏說
The Iraqi Ministry of the Interior
伊拉克內政部寄了這封信
sent this letter to the UN
給聯合國
stating that Omar has links to terrorist groups.
說奧馬爾跟恐怖組織有關
This is not true.
這不是真的
Why would someone do this?
為什麼有人要這樣做？
Detective Fusco arrested the injured legionnaire.
法斯克警探逮捕了受傷的兵團士兵
Perhaps, when he wakes up, he can answer that question.
也許他醒了之後，可以回答這個問題
They could be working for a foreign intelligence service.
他們可能是為某個國外情報局工作
They could also be working
也可能是為
for the UN High Commissioner Lapointe.
聯合國高級專員拉普安特工作
His last post
他的上個職位
was head of UN peacekeeping in the Congo.
是剛果的聯合國維和首腦
Among the units under his control
在他控制之下的部隊
was a company of French legionnaires.
就有一家法國外籍兵團公司
Why would Lapointe wanna kill me
為什麼拉普安特要殺我
for trying to help Omar get into the US?
就因為幫奧馬爾入境？
We need to talk to Omar.
我們得跟奧馬爾談談
He could shed some light on this.
他也許能解釋清楚
It's impossible.
不可能
He's being held incommunicado.
他被拘留，禁止通信
We can't even trust his government-appointed lawyer to deliver a message.
不能信任他的政府委派律師去傳息兒
Maybe he'll talk to his new representation.
也許他可以跟他的新代表說
Like I told my last attorney, I'm not talking to you.
我跟上任律師也說過我不會跟你交談的
We're not with the government, Mr. Risha.
我們不是政府的人，瑞捨先生
We're friends of Maria Martinez.
我們是瑪麗亞·馬丁內斯的朋友
Or maybe you work with the people
也許你跟那些人
that are setting me up.
一起串通陷害我
Maria told us how you saved her life in Iraq.
瑪麗亞告訴我們你在伊拉克救她的事
I'm sorry I don't have more proof,
很抱歉我沒有更多證據
but we don't have much time.
但我們時間不多了
Last night, a team of legionnaires
昨晚，一隊外籍兵團
made an attempt on Maria's life.
想要取瑪麗亞的性命
What?
什麼？
- Is she okay? - She's fine.
- 她還好嗎？
- 她沒事
And she's in a safe place.
她現在在安全的地方
But there was something important
你們上次談話時
you wanted to tell Maria
你說有重要的事
during your last conversation?
想告訴瑪麗亞？
About the generators.
那些發電機
The ones at the energy project
她在伊拉克做的
that she worked on in Iraq?
能源工程的發電機？
After Maria left,
瑪麗亞離開之後
the generators were never installed.
發電機沒有安裝
The hydroelectric plant failed.
水電站關閉了
The entire province went dark.
整個省都停電了
Hospitals had no electricity.
醫院沒有電
Patients died on operating tables.
病人死在手術台上
The local police lost control.
當地警察控制不住局面
Within a week, Al-Qaeda moved back in.
一星期之內，基地組織就捲土重來
What happened to the generators?
發電機發生了什麼事？
That's what I wanted to tell Maria.
那就是我想告訴瑪麗亞的
Right before I left, I translated a contract
就在我離開前，我翻譯了一份合同
for the transportation of six generators.
關於轉移六台發電機
A contract signed by whom?
誰簽署的合同？
Are you sure you can protect Maria?
你確定你能保護瑪麗亞嗎？
Yes.
是的
Why?
為什麼這麼問？
Because it was her boss.
因為是她老闆
Ken Davis.
肯·戴維斯
Davis?
戴維斯？
Why would he ship generators all the way to Iraq
他為什麼把發電機一路運到伊拉克
only to turn around and ship them somewhere else?
轉而又運到其他地方？
Maybe he got a better offer.
也許他接了個更好的單
Maria had Davis write
瑪麗亞讓戴維斯為你
a letter of recommendation in your behalf.
寫了封推薦信
That must be where he realized that, if the two of you
他一定是在那時意識到，一旦你倆
were ever reunited, you would tell her
重新聯手，你一定會告訴她
about his involvement with the missing generators.
發電機丟失與他有關
Your asylum request has been denied.
你的庇護請求被拒絕了
<i>Your ride home</i> <i>departs in an hour.</i>
一小時後送你回國
No, this is a mistake. Please!
不，這樣不行，求你們
They'll kill me if I go back!
回去他們會殺了我
Hey!
嘿
<i>I just sent you information</i>
<i>我剛發給你</i>
on a new lead, Detective.
一條新線索的信息，偵探
It appears that Maria's boss redirected
看來瑪麗亞的老闆改變路線
the missing generators in Iraq to an unknown destination.
把伊拉克丟失的發電機轉運到未知的目的地了
How'd he do that?
他怎麼做到的？
I'm not sure, but Omar knew about it.
我不確定，但奧馬爾知情
Ken Davis arranged for him to be deported
肯·戴維斯安排他遣送回伊拉克
<i>back to Iraq</i> <i>where he'll be killed.</i>
<i>他會被殺的</i>
Davis doesn't have that kind of authority.
戴維斯沒那種權力
<i>But he certainly has the resources</i>
<i>但他肯定有資源</i>
<i>to convince</i> <i>a corrupt UN diplomat</i>
<i>說服一個腐敗的聯合國外交官</i>
<i>to do his dirty work.</i>
<i>幫他搞定</i>
Yeah, well, I think I'm gonna have to pay Davis a visit.
對，我覺得我得去拜訪一下戴維斯了
Please hurry, Detective.
麻煩快點，偵探
<i>We haven't much time.</i>
<i>我們沒多少時間了</i>
Why would Davis steal the generators?
戴維斯為什麼要偷發電機？
We're looking into that now.
我們正在調查
I have to get to Omar.
我得去找奧馬爾
You're not going anywhere
你哪也不能去
with the legionnaires still out there.
外籍士兵還在外面
Guy engineered this place with an armored door
這地方有裝甲門
and electromagnetic locks. You're safe here.
和電磁鎖，你在這才安全
You don't understand.
你不明白
They will kill Omar if he returns to Iraq.
要是奧馬爾回到伊拉克，他們會殺了他
Please.
求你了
Are you gonna cry?
你是要哭了嗎？
- What? - Hold on a sec.
- 什麼？
- 等等
You and Omar were more than just business associates,
你跟奧馬爾不止是商業夥伴
weren't you?
對吧？
Every time I ran into a problem--
每次我遇到麻煩
this sheikh, that tribe, this corrupt official--
酋長，部落，貪官
it was always Omar who solved it.
都是奧馬爾解決的
By bringing people together.
他把人聚到一起
That's why I fell in love with him.
所以我愛上他了
He would take me to the desert at night to drink cinnamon tea
他會在晚上帶我去沙漠喝肉桂茶
and count the stars.
數星星
Have you ever been to the desert at night?
你晚上去過沙漠嗎？
The only thing I remember about the desert
關於沙漠我只記得
is wiping the film
要抹掉
off the top of a warm glass of camel's milk.
溫駱駝奶上面那層薄膜
That's where the bacteria breed.
那是細菌繁殖的地方
Good advice.
這建議不錯
Omar and I,
我跟奧馬爾
we hoped to get married when he got here.
希望在他來美國後結婚
He deserves asylum.
他應該得到庇護
I have to stop his deportation.
我得阻止他被驅逐出境
I need to get to him.
我得找到他
Maria, you have to trust us.
瑪麗亞，你要相信我們
Why?
為什麼？
My mother was an academic back in Iran.
我媽曾經是伊朗大學教師
When the Ayatollah and his fanatics
1979年阿亞圖拉和他的狂熱分子
took over in '79,
武裝佔領伊朗時
someone risked his life smuggling my mom out of there.
有人冒生命危險帶我媽偷渡出國
- If it weren't for him-- - You'd have never been born.
- 要不是他…
- 你就不會出生
Those fanatics
那些
that could've killed my mom in Iran
在伊朗差點殺了我媽的狂熱分子
are the same fanatics...
跟伊拉克那些要殺奧馬爾的
that will kill Omar if he returns to Iraq.
狂熱分子一樣
Just different stripes.
只是兵種不同
But we're not gonna let that happen.
但我們不會讓這事發生
How are you gonna stop it?
你們要怎麼阻止？
Davis has a UN diplomat in his pocket
戴維斯手上有個聯合國外交官
and false accusations from the Iraqi government.
還有伊拉克政府的誣告
Did you read this?
這個你讀了嗎？
"According to a trusted source beyond reproach,
「根據十分可靠的消息」
Omar Risha has ties to--"
「奧馬爾·瑞捨勾結…」
Wait.
等等
Davis's recommendation?
戴維斯的推薦信？
"Because of his impeccable integrity and trustworthiness,
「鑒於其誠實守信的品質」
Omar is a man beyond reproach."
「奧馬爾是十分可靠的人選」
Davis wrote both letters.
兩封信都是戴維斯寫的
Iraqi government letterhead,
抬頭是伊拉克政府
奧馬爾是十分可靠的人選
根據十分可靠的消息
but the font and the...
但字體和…
the format are the same.
版式是一樣的
He forged it.
這是他偽造的
And the original is in Lapointe's office.
原件在拉普安特辦公室
I have to get it.
我得拿到它
- Oh, you can't get in there. - No, no, I know someone.
- 你進不去的
- 不，那裏有我認識的人
- I know a way. - Maria.
- 我有辦法
- 瑪麗亞
You're not going anywhere.
你哪也不能去
You have to trust us.
你得相信我們
Yes, Maria Martinez is an employee of mine.
對，瑪麗亞·馬丁內斯是我的員工
Something happen to her, Detective?
她出事了嗎，偵探？
You're a big energy guy, right?
你搞能源很有能耐，對吧？
International businessman?
國際商人？
Friends in high places?
在高層有朋友？
Even the UN?
聯合國也有？
If you don't mind, I have a schedule to keep.
不好意思，我有行程安排
Oh, yeah?
是嗎？
You have another meeting scheduled
你跟你聯合國的朋友
with your friend inside the UN?
還要碰個面？
The one you've been calling every day?
每天跟你打電話那人？
What is this?
這是什麼？
Metadata?
元數據？
This is a massive violation of my civil liberties.
這嚴重侵犯了我的公民自由
Oh, we've already issued a warrant
我們已經申請了逮捕令
for your corrupt French pal Lapointe
以企圖謀殺瑪麗亞·馬丁內斯的罪名
for the attempted murder of Maria Martinez.
逮捕你那腐敗的法國朋友拉普安特
As soon as he flips,
一旦他落網
we'll have the forged document you sent to the UN
我們就會拿到那份你發到聯合國
naming Omar Risha a terrorist.
指控奧馬爾·瑞捨為恐怖分子的偽造文件
This is absurd.
真荒謬
Where's my attorney?
我的律師在哪？
See, Omar found out about the generators.
奧馬爾發現了發電機的事
So you had him shipped back, knowing he'd be killed.
所以你送他回去，讓他被殺
Then you tried to kill Maria too.
然後你想把瑪麗亞也殺了
Last I checked,
就我所知
your little NYPD fiefdom
區區紐約警局
doesn't extend into the United Nations.
還管不到聯合國
Good luck using your tin badge to get in there, Detective.
祝你順利用警徽進去，警探
You really think you're a big shot, huh?
你真以為自己是大人物？
Get a couple bureaucrats in your pocket,
手上有幾個官僚
grease the contracts.
買兇殺人
You don't care who dies.
你不在乎別人的生死
Including your own employees.
包括你自己的員工
Unless the DA's ready to charge my client, we're leaving.
地方檢察官沒準備好起訴我的客戶的話，我們就走了
If you're going to wade into international waters,
如果你要涉水國際水域
Detective, I suggest you get a bigger boat.
警探，我建議你找艘更大的船
Any word on Omar?
有奧馬爾的消息嗎？
I could use a drink.
我想喝酒
So could I.
我也是
My boys keep a single malt in here somewhere.
我哥們在這裏藏了瓶純麥酒
Thank God Finch buys top shelf.
謝天謝地，芬奇買了瓶高檔的
Oh, Finch!
芬奇
Damn engineers.
該死的工程師
電壓過載
安全模式已開啟
門已被保護
Mr. Reese, they're loading Omar for deportation.
裏斯先生，他們要把奧馬爾驅逐出境了
We have to do something.
我們得有所行動
I'm going to pursue.
我來跟蹤
<i>No need, Finch. I'm on it.</i>
<i>不用，芬奇，我來處理</i>
Let's hit it.
出發吧
Roger that.
收到
Ms. Shaw, good news.
肖女士，好消息
Mr. Reese has rescued Omar.
裏斯先生已經救出奧馬爾
That's great.
很好
Except we just lost Maria,
不過剛剛瑪麗亞跑了
and the legionnaires are still out there looking for her.
外籍兵團還在外面找她
And what's worse,
更糟糕的是
I think she's headed to Lapointe's office.
我覺得她去拉普安特辦公室了
Straight into the lion's den.
直入虎穴
Please, I have an appointment with Mr. Sevon.
拜託，我跟斯萬先生有約
He's a Greek diplomat. I don't have much time.
他是希臘外交官，我沒多少時間了
Sorry, lady.
抱歉，小姐
No badge, no entry.
沒有徽章不得入內
What's the problem here?
怎麼了？
She's my guest.
她是我的客人
Yes, sir.
是，先生
We have to hurry.
我們得快點
Maria, when I said I'd help, I meant making a few calls--
瑪麗亞，我說能幫忙的意思是打電話…
Lapointe denied Omar's asylum based on a forged letter
拉普安特因為一封偽造的伊拉克政府的信
from the Iraqi government.
拒絕庇護奧馬爾
That letter is in Lapointe's office, and I need to get to it.
那封信在拉普安特辦公室，我得拿到它
This is absurd.
這太荒謬了
We can't just break into the High Commissioner's office.
我們不能闖進高級專員的辦公室
There are proper channels we can follow.
我們可以通過適當的渠道解決
Davis conspired with Lapointe to have Omar killed.
戴維斯和拉普安特要殺奧馬爾
And now they want me dead too.
現在他們還想殺我
What? Why would they do that?
什麼？他們為什麼這麼做？
To cover up the theft of six generators in Iraq.
掩蓋在伊拉克偷了六台發電機的行徑
Look, I will explain the rest later,
剩下的我一會再跟你解釋
but right now I need to get that letter.
現在我得拿到那封信
I'll take you as far as Lapointe's office.
我只能把你帶到拉普安特辦公室
But then the rest is up to you.
剩下的靠你自己了
Thank you.
謝謝
You're not a guard.
你不是守衛
And you're not a terrorist.
你也不是恐怖分子
We know you saved Maria's life in Iraq.
我們知道你在伊拉克救了瑪麗亞
We're here to return the favor.
我們來這投桃報李
That's why you're helping me?
你們就為此幫我？
Let's just say we all know what it's like to leave someone behind.
這麼說吧，我們都知道丟下某人的感受
I love Maria.
我愛瑪麗亞
From the first time I met her.
一見鍾情
Where is she now?
她現在在哪？
She's headed to the UN to get evidence
她去聯合國拿證據
to bring down Lapointe and Davis.
扳倒拉普安特和戴維斯
But not if they get to her first.
就怕他們先找到她
We'll we've got to get her out of there before it's too late.
趁還來得及，我們得帶她離開
Are you really suggesting we break into the United Nations?
你真想讓我們闖進聯合國？
They have triple-layered security.
他們有三重安保
<i>Infrared cameras</i> <i>with motion detection.</i>
<i>帶運動檢測功能的紅外線攝像機</i>
I have an idea.
我有個主意
But it's going to require a smoke screen
但需要煙幕
and a big-ass truck.
和一輛大卡車
I'm in position outside the UN compound.
我已經在聯合國大樓外就位
Gonna need to step on it, Reese.
該行動了，裏斯
<i>Ready on this end.</i>
<i>這邊已就緒</i>
Open wide, sister.
散開點，小姐妹
There's a report of smoke on the fourth floor.
四樓報告有煙霧
Call 911.
打911
Fire Department's already here.
消防隊已經來了
We need to evacuate the building.
大樓人員得撤離
Stop playing with the horn, Lionel.
別玩喇叭了，萊諾
Ever since I was a kid,
我從小
I always wanted to drive one of these things.
就想開這種車
Here, you're gonna need this.
拿著，你會需要的
Have you told anyone about Lapointe?
你向別人提過拉普安特嗎？
The original of the letter has to be here somewhere.
信的原件一定在這裏
We should stop while we're ahead.
現在收手還來得及
I am not leaving until I clear Omar's name.
奧馬爾罪名未洗，我是不會走的
Find anything on Davis, Finch?
有戴維斯的信息嗎，芬奇？
Seems he's deleted all his email correspondence.
好像他刪除了所有的郵件
無信息
Ms. Groves, I'm a bit occupied at the moment.
葛洛弗女士，我現在有點忙
Try "Habur Gate," Harold.
試試「哈布爾河閘」，哈羅德
"Habur Gate"?
「哈布爾河閘」？
What does that mean?
什麼意思？
哈布爾·河閘
I don't know.
我不知道
But you're welcome.
不過不用謝
Oh, and, by the way...
噢，還有…
I'm borrowing your dog.
借你的狗用用
<i>Customs clearance.</i>
<i>報關單</i>
進口報單
<i>Six generators.</i>
<i>6台發電機</i>
Requested by...
訂貨人…
Oh, no.
噢，不
Where's the fire, <i>mes amis?</i>
火在哪，<i>朋友？</i>
Here.
看
- I found it. - Good.
- 我找到了
- 很好
We should go.
我們該走了
- He could be here any minute. - What the hell?
- 他隨時會回來
- 怎麼回事？
I should have known it was you when I received a call from the guards.
警衛打來電話，我就知道是你
And what are you doing here?
你在這裏幹嘛？
Excusez-moi, Monsieur Lapointe.
很抱歉，拉普安特先生
I didn't know you spoke French.
你會說法語？
That's the first thing they teach you in the Foreign Legion.
外籍兵團教的第一門課
Consider this payback for what you did to my friend.
就當這個是報復你害我朋友
What's so funny?
很好笑嗎？
Second round is always more accurate than the first.
第二發應該比第一發准
What second round?
什麼第二發？
You're not even holding a gun.
你又沒有槍
I wasn't talking about me.
我說的不是我
Excusez-moi!
抱歉！
So much for payback.
報復到此為止
Come on, come on.
快走
It's a shame, really.
真可惜，真的
After all I did to help you.
畢竟我幫過你
You're working with Davis? Why?
你和戴維斯一夥的，為什麼？
You don't understand how the real world works.
你不明白這個世界
I learned a long time ago, as a legionnaire based in Rwanda.
很久以前在盧旺達的兵團時，我就明白了
They used us to protect those who committed genocide.
他們利用我們保護搞種族屠殺的人
Realpolitiks.
政治現實
<i>This is about greed,</i> <i>not politics.</i>
<i>這是貪婪，無關政治</i>
You have no loyalty.
你是牆頭草
Look at where your loyalty has landed you.
你不是，卻走到了這一步
You know the worst thing about dying on a UN property?
你知道死在聯合國最糟糕的是什麼嗎？
Extraterritorial privileges.
治外法權
Makes it very difficult for the NYPD to investigate.
紐約警察很難調查
Somebody call 911?
有人打911？
Drop the gun.
放下槍
Or what, Detective?
不然怎樣，警官？
Or I'm gonna get <i>Realpolitik-y</i> <i>on your ass.</i>
不然我就<i>現實地踢你屁股</i>
You and Davis stole the generators from Iraq.
你和戴維斯從伊拉克偷了發電機
You have no proof.
你沒有證據
"Habur Gate" ring a bell?
「哈布爾河閘」，聽說過嗎？
<i>Habur Gate. That's</i> <i>the border crossing</i> between Iraq and Turkey.
<i>哈布爾河閘，在伊拉克和土耳其邊界</i>
Next time have someone else sign the customs form.
下次找別人簽報關單
Go figure.
原來
Turns out immunity doesn't stop you from bleeding.
豁免權也止不住你的血
That's what I call diplomacy.
這就是外交
Maria.
瑪麗亞
Oh, my God, I can't believe you're here!
上帝啊，不敢相信你來了！
Gonna need to step it up, boys.
快點吧，夥計們
Sounds like the cavalry's on its way.
好像援兵到了
- Come on. Let's go. - We gotta go!
- 來吧，快走
- 得走了！
How'd you find this place?
你怎麼找到這裏的？
Someone recommended the view.
有人說景色好
The office of the High Commissioner
高級專員辦公室
just sent this over.
剛送來這個
Congratulations.
恭喜
Your asylum's officially been approved.
你的避難申請批准了
And Sevon?
斯萬呢？
Greece revoked his diplomatic immunity.
希臘取消了他的外交豁免權
NYPD arrested him for the murder of Lapointe.
紐約警察以謀殺拉普安特的罪名逮捕了他
Thank you, Detective, and your friends.
謝謝你，警官，還有你的朋友
For everything.
謝謝你們做的一切
Welcome to New York.
歡迎來到紐約！
Hey, what's up?
嘿，怎麼了？
Thought the case was closed.
我以為結案了
You did good tonight, Lionel.
你今晚不錯啊，萊諾
Glass of champagne, best you got.
來杯最好的香檳
I thought you didn't drink.
我以為你不喝酒
March 20th.
3月20號
Persian New Year.
波斯新年
I thought you didn't care about foreign cultures.
我以為你不關心異國文化
That's what's great about New York.
紐約的妙處就在這裏
You don't have to travel to learn about other cultures.
瞭解文化不用出門
They all come here.
它們在這裏彙集
My father brought my mother here on their first date.
我父親第一次約會我母親就是在這
No kidding.
真的
Nice place.
不錯啊
It's changed names a couple times,
改了幾次名字
but the view's still the same.
但景色還是一樣
Get outta here, Fusco.
你走吧，法斯克
Happy new year, Sameen.
新年快樂，薩敏
It may not be the desert stars,
也許不是沙漠的星空
but there's nothing like the New York City skyline.
但紐約的夜色無與倫比
<i>And Davis?</i>
<i>戴維斯呢？</i>
According to Detective Fusco,
據法斯克警探說
he's flown the coop.
他逃了
And with his international connections...
有這麼多海外關係…
he could be anywhere.
他選擇很多
Maybe one of our allies will scoop him up.
也許我們的盟友會挖出他來
Speaking of allies...
說到盟友…
I do hope that Root isn't feeding Bear any chocolate.
但願根姐別喂大熊巧克力
Sit. Sit.
坐下
I've secured the generators you were looking for.
我搞到了你要的發電機
They shipped from Akcaabat Port last week.
上周已經從阿克恰阿巴德港發貨了
What are you trying to power? New York City?
你想為什麼供電？紐約？
Sorry to hear about your friend Sevon.
你朋友斯萬的事，我很抱歉
But just as well.
不過也好
He worked for an antiquated institution.
他效命的組織很古老
Hard to believe that Nation States still think
難以相信聯合國還認為
they have any influence, even in cooperation.
他們還有影響力，還能合作
Sevon got sloppy.
斯萬失手了
I can't afford such liabilities.
我承受不了這種紕漏
Then lucky for me I'm careful.
幸運的是我很小心
Indeed.
確實
Walk.
走吧
Go blind.
關閉
追蹤對像
化名：約翰·格裏爾
體重：84,024千克
間隔：1.023秒
距離：0.976米
音頻輸入飽和
目標丟失
正在轉為GPS搜尋
Which way, Bear?
哪邊，大熊？
Attaboy.
好孩子
Hello, Ms. Groves.
你好，葛洛弗女士
Sit, boy.
坐下，小子
I commend your tracking abilities.
我讚賞你的跟蹤技能
Sense of smell is often the most neglected of the five senses.
五感中，嗅覺最容易被忽視
And one which machines can't replicate.
這一點機器也沒辦法
At least... not yet.
起碼…目前沒有
When I was a boy, we had a foxhound called--
我小時候，有只獵狐犬名叫…
Churchill.
丘吉爾
Shall we cut to the chase?
我們開門見山吧
You have some things that don't belong to you--
你偷了點東西…
two hard drives, a superconducting chip,
兩塊硬盤，一個超級芯片
and six generators.
6台發電機
Which means,
也就是說
either your planning to bring Samaritan online...
要不你在計劃使撒瑪利亞上線
or you're the world's most ambitious gamer.
要不你就是世界最大的玩家
Why waste time arguing about small battles,
何必為小衝突浪費口舌
when we could be discussing the larger war?
我們可以談談更大的戰場
Perhaps you and I have more in common than you think.
或許你我的共同點比你想像的要多
I don't think so.
我不覺得
I want the machine to be free.
我想要機器自由
You wanna control it.
你想控制它
I won't bore you with academic theories
我不想用沉悶的理論
about competing civilizations.
解釋文明的競爭
It's human nature to want to control the means
人類的本性就是控制渠道獲得
to wealth, hmm?
財富，嗯？
Whether it be salt or gold or oil.
無論是鹽，金子或者石油
Or information.
抑或是信息
It is the new currency.
這是新通貨
And if someone's gonna control it,
如果有人要控制
it might as well be you?
不如乾脆是你？
Imagine...
想像一下…
what it would be like to merge, permanently.
聯手起來會如何，永久的
I could use someone with such capabilities.
我需要有能力的人
And why would I do that?
我為什麼要合作？
Because I know what you know to be true, Ms. Groves, hmm?
因為我知道你所知不假，葛洛弗女士
Everyone thinks you're crazy.
大家都以為你瘋了
But I don't.
我不這麼想
Because we understand what's coming.
因為我們知道未來
What's about to happen.
將會發生什麼
Don't we?
不是嗎？
And what makes you think you're in any position
你憑什麼以為你有資格
to negotiate?
討價還價？
<i>Touche.</i>
<i>不錯啊</i>
I never feel civilized...
我一直覺得很不文明
negotiating from the end of a barrel.
談判時被人用槍威脅…
Either end.
或用槍威脅別人
Shall we call this one a draw?
這次算平手吧？
Very well.
那好
Perhaps next time we meet
或許下次我們再見…
you'll reconsider my offer.
你會重新考慮我的提議
谢谢观赏
TLF字幕组欢迎你
TLF中文字幕站 http://sub.eastgame.org/
微博地址：http://t.sina.com.cn/tlfsubs